Guide to the Ernst Toller Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Ernst Toller papers
1917-1978
1933-1939
MS 498
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
8.77
(29 boxes)
The major part of the papers is made up of a nearly complete collection of Ernst Toller's plays printed in German and in English translation, together with copies of his articles (1917-1939) which were gathered from newspapers and periodicals from many countries by John M. Spalek, editor of Toller's works. Also assembled by Spalek and added to the papers are articles, books, and dissertations (1922-1972) about Toller in both German and English. The personal papers stem from the last five years of Toller's life and consist of manuscripts for eight plays written between 1934 and 1938, typescripts of short stories in English and German, speeches, memorabilia and photographs. A small amount of correspondence (1933-1939) is largely concerned with his Spanish Relief Project, devoted to raising funds to alleviate the consequences of the Civil War in Spain. Notable correspondents include Hewlett Johnson, Dean of Canterbury, Pablo Picasso, H. G. Wells, and Frederick Wertham.
Toller, Ernst, 1893-1939
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Sidney Kaufman, 1954, and from John M. Spalek, 1977. Gift of Bert Kasties, 1991. Purchased from A Piece of History, 2011.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series and two additions: I. Correspondence, Manuscripts, Miscellaneous Items. II. Published Works. III. Works About Toller.
Scope and Contents
The Ernst Toller Papers make it possible to examine Toller's development as a political writer and speaker as well as a dramatist. The personal papers are concentrated in the last years of Toller's life, covering 1934 to 1939. Correspondence dates primarily from the year 1938. In addition, the personal papers include manuscript and typscript copies of Toller's plays written between 1935 and 1939.
A major feature of the Ernst Toller Papers is the nearly complete collection of Toller's plays in German and English translation. Also of special interest is a large collection of Toller's occasional pieces which originally appeared in newspapers and periodicals in several countries. These works span Toller's entire writing career. They were collected by John M. Spalek, editor of Toller's works, and have been brought together here in the Ernst Toller Papers.
Toller's fame before 1933 rested almost exclusively on his plays. Yet after 1930 Toller's political writings increased until in exile they actually exceeded his dramatic works. The papers as a whole reflect this trend, notably in the large amount of material devoted to Toller's involvement with the Spanish Relief Project.
In addition to Toller's own published and unpublished work, the papers contain valuable critical writings on Toller and his work.
For the most complete critical bibliography of works by and about Toller see John M. Spalek's Ernst Toller and His Critics, University Press of Virginia, Charlottesville, 1968.
The papers are arranged in three series and two additions: Series. I CORRESPONDENCE, MANUSCRIPTS AND MISCELLANEOUS ITEMS; Series II. PUBLISHED WORKS; Series III. WORKS ABOUT TOLLER.
Series I, CORRESPONDENCE, MANUSCRIPTS AND MISCELLANEOUS ITEMS, contains some correspondence concerning the publication of Toller's plays, but consists primarily of correspondence which deals with Toller's efforts to seek funds and support for his Spanish Relief Project in 1938. Correspondents of note include Hewlett Johnson, Dean of Canterbury, Cosmo Gordon Lang, Archbishop of Canterbury, Pablo Picasso, H.G. Wells and Frederic Wertham.
Series I also contains manuscripts of Toller's plays, articles, speeches and short stories. Most of the articles and speeches concern the Spanish Relief Project and Toller's opposition to Nazism.
The photographs in Series I include those of Toller alone and in groups, of Toller's theatrical productions, and photographs of war-torn Spain in 1938.
Materials in Series I concerning the Spanish Relief Project include statistics and reports on the food shortage in Spain, numerous newspaper clippings from various countries, and leaflets and memoranda.
At the end of Series I are various miscellaneous items.
Series II, PUBLISHED WORKS, is divided into two sections: Books and Plays and Miscellaneous Minor Works and Reprints. The latter contains a collection of the occasional works of Toller, and of portions of his works reprinted either in periodicals or in pamphlet form. Among the miscellaneous works are essays, speeches, newspaper and periodical articles, interviews with and newspaper articles about Toller. Included here are transcripts of his trial in Bavaria, 1918-1919. The works are mostly in German and English translation and are all electrostatic copies.
Series III, WORKS ABOUT TOLLER, includes books, dissertations and articles about Toller and his work. Also included are a student play based on Toller's life, and a poem written after Toller's death by W. H. Auden.
The Ernst Toller Papers were purchased by Yale University from Sidney Kaufman in 1954 and John M. Spalek in 1977.
Biographical / Historical
Ernst Toller, German dramatist and political activist, was born of Jewish parents on December 1, 1893, in Samotschin, a small town near Bromberg. After receiving his primary and secondary education in Samotschin and Bromberg, he attended the University of Grenoble, France.
At the outbreak of World War I, Toller returned to Germany from France. He enlisted in the army and served on the western front. Discharged from the army because of poor health, Toller continued his studies at the universities of Munich and Heidelberg.
When the Bavarian Revolution broke out in Germany in 1918, Toller was prominent in the revolutionary government. For activities connected with this position he later served five year's imprisonment.
The term in prison was a prolific period for Toller. Plays which were successfully produced during his confinement include Die Wandlung (1919), Masse-Mensch (1921), Die Maschinenstürmer (1922), and Hinkemann (1924).
Toller's play Hoppla, wir leben! opened in Berlin in 1927. The year 1930 saw the opening of Feuer aus den Kesseln! in Berlin and the publication of Quer Durch.
Toller went to Switzerland in 1933. During the same year he was deprived of his citizenship by the Nazi government, his property was confiscated, and his books were burned. He fled to England and subsequently became a British subject. At the end of 1933, Toller's autobiography, Eine Jugend in Deutschland, was published.
In 1935 Toller produced Draw the Fires! in Manchester and published Briefe aus dem Gefängnis. No More Peace! opened in London in 1936.
Toller made his first trip to the United States in 1929. He again came to this country in 1936 with his wife, Christiane Grautoff, whom he had married the previous year, and lectured both here and in Canada on the dangers of Hitler and fascism.
In 1937 Toller was hired to write film scripts for Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer. During this time he resided mostly in Santa Monica, California.
Toller traveled to Spain in 1938 and witnessed the suffering of the civilian population in the midst of a civil war. He initiated a large-scale relief project for civilians on both sides of the Spanish Civil War and secured the cooperation of the United States and several European countries in raising money for food suplies. The bulk of Toller's correspondence and essayistic prose from this period reflects his deep commitment to aiding the Spanish refugees.
Toller's last play, Pastor Hall, was published in the spring of 1939.
Toller committed suicide on May 22, 1939, in New York City.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
German literature; Literature -- History and criticism; Europe; Germany -- History -- 1933-1945; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939; Authors; Aschberg, Olof, 1877-1960; Brailsford, Henry Noel, 1873-1958; Casparsson, Ragnar, 1893-1978; Cerf, Bennett, 1898-1971; Clark, Barrett H. (Barrett Harper), 1890-1953; Dunn, James C. (James Clement), 1890-1979; Eidem, Erling, 1880-1972; Greenwood, Arthur, 1880-1954; Jacobson, Hans, 1872-; Jensen, Christian, 1879-; Johnson, Hewlett, 1874-1966; Koht, Halvdan, 1873-1965; Lang, Cosmo Gordon, 1864-1945; Manning, William T.; Marley, Dudley Leigh Aman, Baron, 1884-1952; McIntyre, Marvin Hunter, 1878-1943; Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973; Pickett, Clarence, 1884-1965; Ríos, Fernando de los, 1879-1949; Roberts, Walter St. Clair Howland, 1893-1978; Savage, Michael Joseph, 1872-1940; Searle, Robert W. (Robert Wyckoff), 1894-1967; Ström, Fredrik, 1880-1948; Temple, William, 1881-1944; Toller, Ernst, 1893-1939; Wells, H. G. (Herbert George), 1866-1946
- Correspondence, Manuscripts and Miscellaneous Items, 1926-(1934-1939)-1966; Series I; 2.3' (6 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence is arranged chronologically.
  Manuscripts of plays and short stories are arranged alphabetically within form. Articles and speeches are each arranged chronologically.
  Photographs are arranged by subject.
  Spanish Relief Project materials and various miscellaneous items appear at the end of the series.
  - Correspondence
    - 1934-1939 July 14, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-12)
  - Plays
    - The Blind Goddess, published fragment with uncut pages, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Blind Man's Buff, handwritten fragments in German and English, [1936?] (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Blind Man's Buff, typed fragments in English, [1936?] (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Reviews and excerpts from reviews of the British production of Blind Man's Buff, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Draw the Fires!, typewritten acting version in eleven scenes, [1935-1936?] (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Scrapbook with text of Draw the Fires! with notes and corrections in Toller's hand (Additional pages of notes and text laid in last page removed), 1935 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Papers removed from last page of scrapbook with text of Draw the Fires!, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Draw the Fires!, typewritten acting version in ten scenes. Revised for the American stage by Joseph Liss and Oscar Saul, [1938?] (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Musical score for Draw the Fires! by Hans Eisler, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Reviews and typed excerpts from reviews of Draw the Fires!, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Outline for Forget Europe, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Nie Wieder Friede, Ms (typescript)with corrections, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Lyrics translated into English by W. H. Auden, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - The Night Is Far Spent (first version of Pastor Hall in English), undated
      General
      See: box 3, folder 28
    - Reviews and programs for No More Peace!, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Pastor Hall, Ms (typescript)with first and second versions of the final scene, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Pastor Hall, Ms (typescript) with second version of the final scene, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - (First version of Pastor Hall in English) The Night Is Far Spent, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Pastor Hall, Ms (typescript) translated into English by Stephen Spender (three copies), [1938?] (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Pastor Hall, Ms (typescript) translted into English by Stephen Spender, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Der Weg Nacht Indien, draft for a film script in Toller's hand and typescript with corrections, [1937?] (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Worldly Requiem. Choral Work. Ms (typescript) translated by Alexander Henderson (two versions), undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Articles
    - 1932-1936 (Box 3, Folder 33-35)
    - 1937-1939 (Box 4, Folder 36-38)
    - About the Spanish Civil War, 1936-1938, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - On Hitler and Nazism, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - About politics in Germany, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - About life in prison, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Speeches
    - 1926, 1933-1936 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - 1937 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - 1936-1937, 1965
      See: box 27, folder 94
    - 1938 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - About the Spanish Relief Project, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - About Hitler and Nazism, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - About politics in Germany, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Short Stories
    - "Begegnung auf der Landstrasse", undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - "Begegnung in Barcelona", 1938 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - "Death of a Mother", 1939 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - "Grabbed by the Tail", pre-1935 August (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - "The Interrogatory", undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - "Marriage in Morocco", n. d. (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - "Meeting in Barcelona", 1938 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - "Meeting on the Road", undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - "Resurrected from Death", undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - "Der Tod einer Mutter", 1939 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - "The Victor of Kertsch", undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - "You have all heard the story…", undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Photographs
    - Sculpture and reproductions of sketches of Toller, 1936, undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Toller alone, undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Toller in groups, [1919?], 1924 November 1, undated (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Toller's theatrical productions, 1927 October 7, 1937 February 26-27, 1937 June 17, undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Spain, 1938, undated (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Collected by Toller, 1933, undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Spanish Relief Project
    - Statistics on food rationing in Spain, 1937 August - 1938 July (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Reports on the food shortage in Spain, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Newspaper clippings from various countries, 1938 Aug, October-December (Box 6, Folder 60-62)
    - Newspaper clippings from New York and London newspapers, [1938?], 1939 January (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Leaflets and memoranda, 1936, 1938, undated (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Research notes and newspaper clippings about Spain, 1938, undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Miscellaneous Items
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings. Includes brief reviews of Toller's plays and articles on Toller's anti-Nazi speeches, 1936-1938 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Typescript copies of articles from New York newspapers. Includes articles on Hitler and Nazism, 1932, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - American Gentile, 1936 September - October (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - The Storm, 1936 October 15 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - Newspaper clippings on the German theater, including the effects of Nazism, 1934-1937 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - Programs for Toller's U.S. lecture tour, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - Miscellaneous addresses and bill, 1937 January 7, undated (Box 6, Folder 71)
    - Phonotapes of Toller reading from Hoppla, wirleben! and poetry and recording of a radio discussion between Toller and Alfred Mühr, undated (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - Three Essays on Masks, Ms (typescript) by Eugene O'Neill, 1932-1933 (Box 6, Folder 73)
- Published Works, 1917-1978; Series II; 6.3' (19 boxes)
  Books and Plays are grouped by language. The majority of these works are in German and appear at the beginning of the section. English translations comprise the next largest group and appear after the German editions. Following these are translations of Toller's works into six other languages.
  Miscellaneous Minor Works and Reprints are arranged chronologically by the date of the periodical in which they appear. In the case of whole items they are listed according to the date of the imprint rather than according to the original date of publication.
  - Books and Plays
    - Gesammelte Werke. Hrsg. von John M. Spalek und Wolfgang Frühwald. 5 Bd. München: Carl Hanser Verlag, c1978. (Box 7)
    - Ausgewählte Schriften. Mit Geleitworten von Bodo Uhse und Bruno Kaiser. Hrsg. von der Deutschen Akademie der Künste zu Berlin. [1. Aufl.] Berlin: Verlag Volk and Welt, 1959. (Box 8)
    - AusgewählteSchriften. Mit Geleitworten von Bodo Uhse and Bruno Kaiser. Hrsg. von der Deutschen Akademie der Künste zu Berlin. [ 2. Aufl.] Berlin: Verlag Volk and Welt, 1961. (Box 8)
    - Die blinde Göttin: Schauspielin fünf Akten. Berlin: Gustav Kiepenheuer Bühnenvertriebs-GmbH, 1959. (Box 8)
    - Briefe aus dem Gefangnis. Amsterdam: Querido Verlag, 1935. (Box 8)
    - Briefe aus dem Gefangnis. Amsterdam: Querido Verlag, 1935. (Box 9)
    - Brokenbrow. Translated by Vera Mendel with drawings by Georg Grosz. London: Nonesuch Press, 1926.
      See: box 25, folder 80
    - Deutsche Revolution. Das Tagebuch, II, 12(26 März 1921): 358-365. (Box 9)
    - Der deutsche Hinkemann. Eine Tragödie in drei Akten. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1923. (Box 9)
    - Der entfesselte Wotan, eine Komödie. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer, 1923. (Box 9)
    - Der entfesselte Wotan, eine Komödie. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer, 1924. (Box 9)
    - Der entfesselte Wotan. Komödie. Berlin: Gustav Kiepenheuer Bühnenvertriebs-GmbH, 1959. (Box 9)
    - Feuer aus den Kesseln, Historisches Schauspiel. Anhang: Historische Dokumente. Berlin: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1930. (Box 10)
    - Feuer aus den Kesseln, Historisches Schauspiel. Berlin: Oesterheld & Co., 1930.
      See: box 25, folder 81
    - Feuer aus den Kesseln, Historisches Schauspiel. Anhang: Historische Dokumente. Berlin: Henschelverlag. Abteilung Bühnenvertrieb [1958]. (Box 10)
    - Gedichte der Gefangenen, ein Sonettenkreis. Munchen: Kurt Wolff Verlag, 1923. (Box 10)
    - Hinkemann. Eine Tragödie. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1924. (Box 10)
    - Hinkemann. Eine Tragödie in drei Akten. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1924. (Box 10)
    - Hinkemann. Eine Tragödie. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1925. (Box 10)
    - Hinkemann. Hrsg. von Artur Müller and Helmut Schlein. Emsdetten: Verlag Lechte, 1954. (Box 10)
    - Hinkemann. Hrsg. von Wolfgang Frühwald. Stuttgart: Philipp Reclam, 1971. (Box 10)
    - Hoppla, wir leben! Ein Vorspiel undfünf Akte. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1927. (Box 10)
    - Hoppla, wir leben! and Feuer aus den Kesseln. Mit einen Nachwort von Alfred Klein. Leipzig: Philipp Reclam, 1962. (Box 10)
    - Eine Jugend in Deutschland. Amsterdam: Querido Verlag, 1933. (Box 11)
    - Eine Jugend in Deutschland. Amsterdam: Querido Verlag, 1936. (Box 11)
    - Eine Jugend in Deutschland. Reinbek: Rowohlt, 1962. (Box 11)
    - Eine Jugend in Deutschland. Leipzig: Philipp Reclam, 1970. (Box 11)
    - Die Maschinenstürmer. Ein Drama aus der Zeit der Ludditenbewegung in England in fünf of Akten and einem Vorspiel. Leipzig Wien Zürich: E.P. Tal & Co. Verlag, 1922. (Box 12)
    - Die Maschinenstürmer. Ein Drama aus der Zeit der Ludditenbewegung in England in fünf Akten and einem Vorspiel. Leipzig Wien: Zürich: E.P. Tal & Co. Verlag, 1924. (Box 12)
    - Die Maschinenstürmer. Ein Drama aus der Zeit der Ludditenbewegung in England in fünf Akten und einem Vorspiel. Leipzig Wien Zürich: E.P. Tal & Co. Verlag, 1927. (Box 12)
    - Die Maschinenstürmer. Ein Drama aus der Zeit der Ludditenbewegung in England in fünf Akten und einem Vorspiel. Für den Schulgebrauch Eingerichtet von Hanns Vogts. Berlin: Freier Schulverlag, undated (Box 12)
    - Masse-Mensch. Ein Stück aus der Sozialen Revolution des 20. Jahrhunderts. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1922. (Box 13)
    - Masse-Mensch. Ein Stück aus der Sozialen Revolution des 20. Jahrhunderts. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1924. (Box 13)
    - Masse-Mensch. Ein Stück aus der Sozialen Revolution des 20. Jahrhunderts. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1925. (Box 13)
    - Masse-Mensch. Ein Stück aus der Sozialen Revolution des 20. Jahrhunderts. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1928. (Box 13)
    - Prosa Briefe Dramen Gedichte. Mit einem Vorwort von Kurt Hiller. Reinbek: Rowohlt., 1961. (Box 13)
    - Quer Durch. Reisebilder und Reden. Berlin: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1930. (Box 13)
    - Quer Durch. Reisebilder und Reden. Berlin: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1930. (Box 14)
    - Die Rache des verhöhnten Liebhabers: oder, Frauenlist und Mannerlist: ein galantes Puppenspiel in zwei Akten frei nach einer Geschichte des Kardinals Bandello. Berlin: Paul Cassirer, 1925. (Box 14)
    - Das Schwalbenbuch. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1924. (Box 14)
    - Das Schwalbenbuch. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1927. (Box 14)
    - Der Tag des Proletariats. Requiem den gemordeten Brüdern. Zwei Chorwerke. Berlin: Verlagsgenossenschaft "Freiheit" e.G.m.b.H., 1920. (Box 15)
    - Tag des Proletariats. Requiem den gemordeten Brüdern. Zwei Sprechchore. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1925. (Box 15)
    - Vormorgen. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1924. (Box 15)
    - Die Wandlung. Das Ringen eines Menschen. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer, 1920. (Box 15)
    - Die Wandlung. Das Ringen eines Menschen. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer, 1922, 1924, 1925. (Box 15)
    - The Blind Goddess. A Play in Five Acts. London: John Lane the Bodley Head, 1934. (Box 15)
    - Blind Man's Buff. A Play in Three Acts. Ernst Toller and Denis Johnston. London: Jonathan Cape, 1938. (Box 15)
    - Draw the Fires! An Historical Play. Translated by Edward Crankshaw. London: John Lane the Bodley Head, 1935. (Box 16)
    - I Was a German, an Autobiography. Translated by Edward Crankshaw. London: John Lane the Bodley Head, 1934 (Box 16)
    - I Was a German. The Autobiography of Ernst Toller. Translated by Edward Crankshaw. New York: William Morrow and Co, 1934. (Box 16)
    - Letters from Prison. Including Poems and a New Version of "The Swallow Book ." Translated by R. Ellis Roberts. illus. London: John Lane the Bodley Head, 1936. (Box 17)
    - Look Through the Bars. Letters from Prison, Poems, and a New Version of "The Swallow Book." Translated by R. Ellie Roberts. New York Toronto: Farrar & Rinehart, Inc., 1937. (Box 17)
    - The Machine-Wreckers. A Drama of the English Luddites in a Prologue and Five Acts. English version by Ashley Dukes. London: Benn Brothers, Limited, 1923. (Box 17)
    - The Machine-Wreckers. A Drama of the English Luddites in a Prologue and Five Acts. English version by Ashley Dukes. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1923. (Box 17)
    - Man and the Masses (Masse Mensch). A Play of the Social Revolution in Seven Scenes. 1st ed. Translated by Louis Untermeyer. Garden City: Doubleday, Page & co., 1924. (Box 17)
    - Masses and Man. A Fragment of the Social Revolution of the Twentieth Century. Translated by Vera Mendel. London: The None-such Press, 1923-1924 (Box 18)
    - Masses and Man. A Fragment of the Social Revolution of the Twentieth Century. Translated by Vera Mendel. London: The None-such Press, 1926. (Box 18)
    - Masses and Man. A Fragment of the Social Revolution of the Twentieth Century. Translated by Vera Mendel. London: John Lane the Bodley Head, 1934. (Box 18)
    - No More Peace! A. Thoughtful Comedy. Translated by Edward Crankshaw. Lyrics translated and adapted by W.H. Auden. Music by Herbert Murrill. New York Toronto: Farrar & Rinehart, Inc., 1937. (Box 19)
    - Pastor Hall. A Play in Three Acts. Translated by Stephen Spender. London: John Lane the Bodley Head, 1939. (Box 19)
    - Pastor Hall. Translated by Stephen Spender and Hugh Hunt. Blind Man's Buff. Ernst Toller and Denis Johnston. 1st print. New York: Random House, 1939. (Box 19)
    - Seven Plays. Comprising The Machine-Wreckers, Transfiguration, Masses and Man, Hinkemann, Hoppla! Such Is Life!, The Blind Goddess, Draw the Fires!Together with Mary Baker Eddy by Ernst Toller and Hermann Kesten. With a new introduction by the author. London: John Lane the Bodley Head, 1935. (Box 19)
    - Seven Plays. Comprising The Machine-Wreckers, Transfiguration, Masses and Man, Hinkemann, Hoppla! Such Is Life!, The Blind Goddess, Draw the Fires! Together with Mary Baker Eddy by Ernst Toller and HermannKersten. With a new introduction by the author. New York: Liverwright Publishing Corporation, [1936]. (Box 20)